creativepro.com 2005-12-12

# creativepro.com - Creativepro.com Privacy Policy

    |  This statement discloses the privacy practices for the creativepro.com Web site. When you visit a Web site, you can expect to be notified of: What personally identifiable information of yours is collected; What organization is collecting the information; How the information is used; With whom the information may be shared; What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information; What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the company's control; and How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [webmaster@creativepro.com](mailto:webmaster@creativepro.com). 

**This policy will let you know:**

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours is collected; 
  2. What cookies are and how they are used; 
  3. How your information is used; 
  4. Who is collecting your information; 
  5. With whom your information may be shared; 
  6. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information; 
  7. How you can access or update your information; 
  8. How creativepro treats your personal financial information<; 
  9. The kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information ; 
  10. What else you should know about your online privacy.

* * *

**What personally identifiable information does creativepro.com collect from me?**

IP Addresses: creativepro.com stores the 

[Internet Protocol (IP)](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/TERM/I/IP_address.html#IP) address of your computer when you visit our site. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Web site, and to gather broad demographic information. 

Some personal information is gathered when you register for membership or shop at the creativeproShop. During registration or shopping check-out, creativepro.com asks for your name, e-mail address, and other personal information. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to creativepro.com - you are given a creativepro.com ID and are able to take full advantage of creativepro.com's many offerings. 

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you enter a contest or promotion sponsored by creativepro.com and/or our partners; when you make a purchase at the creativeproShop; when you submit a listing for a Web site; and if you report a problem with our site or one of our services. Creativepro.com also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for internal research. Wherever creativepro.com collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. 

* * *

**What are cookies and how does creativepro.com use them?**

A _cookie_ is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Creativepro.com uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above), when you register as a creativepro.com member, and when you click an ad: 

Creativepro.com uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. Anywhere you are prompted to log-in or that is customizable requires that you accept cookies. 

Generally, we use cookies for: 

  1. **Member Registration:** when you register creativepro.com uses a cookie to store a unique, random user ID. We do not store passwords or any personal information about you. We use this ID to identify you anonymously in our database and to track the pages you visit on our site. Cookies also enable you to visit member-restricted areas of the sites. 
  2. **Ads:** Creativepro.com's advertising system delivers a one-time cookie to better track ad impressions and click rates. 

If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. 

**You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser.** You do not need to have cookies turned on to use the creativepro.com site. However, you do need cookies to log in as a member or participate actively in our forums. 

* * *

**How does creativepro.com use my information?**

Creativepro.com uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience on our site, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

  * As stated above, creativepro.com uses information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, contests, message boards, and shopping at the creativeproShop. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (daily or weekly, depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. Creativepro.com never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers or partners. 
  * When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. Creativepro.com does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. 
  * We track search terms entered in Search.com as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 
  * Creativepro.com creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because creativepro.com doesn't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. 
  * The creativeproShop and creativeproBooks are hosted by Amazon.com. All transactions and information gathered during your purchasing experience is the property of Amazon.com. Amazon.com has its own privacy policy and data collection practices. Please visit Amazon.com's [privacy policy](http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/468496/107-6884755-3544550) for more information. CreativeproShop is not responsible for typographical or photographic errors that may appear on this web site. We reserve the right to make adjustments or corrections due to errors, changing market conditions, product discontinuations, or typographic or photographic errors in advertisements or product descriptions. Policies, item availability and prices are subject to change without notice. 

* * *

**Who is collecting information?**

When you are at creativepro.com or creativeproShop.com and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with creativepro.com alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. 

Promotions that run on creativepro.com may be sponsored by companies other than creativepro.com or may be cosponsored by creativepro.com and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared. 

Please be aware that creativepro.com advertisers or Web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those linked Web sites are not covered by this privacy statement. 

* * *

**With whom does creativepro.com share my information?**

As a general rule, creativepro.com will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your explicit permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. 

_Business Partners & Sponsors_: Some or all data collected during a creativepro.com promotion may be shared with a sponsor or partner. If personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. 

Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give creativepro.com permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In most instances, only your e-mail address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer. 

The creativeproShop and creativeproBooks are hosted by Amazon.com. All transactions and information gathered during your purchasing experience is the property of Amazon.com. Amazon.com has its own privacy policy and data collection practices. Please visit Amazon.com's 

[privacy policy](http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/browse/-/468496/107-6884755-3544550) for more information. 

Merchants listed in creativepro.com have separate privacy and data collection practices. Creativepro.com has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their _Information_ link. 

_Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate_: Under confidentiality agreements, creativepro.com may match user information with third party data. Also, creativepro.com discloses aggregated user statistics (e.g., 40% of our members are graphic designers) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. _Business Transfers:_ As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the unlikely event that creativepro.com, Inc. or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will, of course, be one of the transferred assets. _Other_ : creativepro.com may also disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) creativepro.com's rights or property, other creativepro.com users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Creativepro.com may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. 

* * *

**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**

If you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from creativepro.com or our partners, we may occasionally send you e-mail about products and services that we feel might be of interest to you. Only creativepro.com (or agents working on behalf of creativepro.com and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you sign up to be a member. Or, at any time you can easily edit your 

USER PROFILE to no longer receive such offers or mailings. In addition, you will be able to unsubscribe to our mailing list by clicking on an URL in our newsletter that will automatically remove you from our mailing list. 

We use an outside ad company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. 

Except under the special circumstances as previously described, creativepro.com never provides our clients or partners with information that could be used to identify you personally, without first obtaining your express consent. The data that we provide to our clients is always presented in an aggregate manner; therefore, neither the client nor creativepro.com can identify any individual or their associated profile information within that collective data. 

If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests. Creativepro.com does not sell or rent information about individual users to third party marketing and advertising firms. 

* * *

**Correcting and updating personal information?**

You may edit your 

MEMBER PROFILE at any time by using your e-mail address and password. If you have forgotten your password, please go to the membership area and enter your e-mail address in the "Forgot my password" box. Your password will be e-mailed to you immediately. 

Creativepro.com sends regular e-mail updates to members. If you wish to be removed from our mailing list, please click on the _unsubscribe_ URL that appears at the end of each e-mail. Please allow two to three business days for the actual cancellation to take effect. We will never share your e-mail address with marketers or other external parties without first receiving your permission. 

_Links:_ creativepro.com currently provides links to a number of other WWW sites that we believe offer useful information and services for our members. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and procedures maintained by these external sites, including whether they collect and sell personal information about users. We suggest contacting these sites directly for information on their data collection and disbursement policies. 

* * *

**How does creativepro.com protect my personal financial information?**

Keeping your personal financial information private is vitally important to us. As with all personal information, creativepro.com will never rent or sell your personal financial information. 

Any time we ask for a credit card number in order to complete a purchase transaction or for verification purposes, we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. 

* * *

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Your creativepro.com account information is password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your account information, including your password, at any time by simply connecting and logging on to the site. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, creativepro.com cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

* * *

**What else should I know about my privacy?**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online -- for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas -- that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

Creatvepro.com and the CreativeproShop are not responsible for typographical or photographic errors that may appear on this web site. We reserve the right to make adjustments or corrections due to errors, changing market conditions, product discontinuations, or typographic or photographic errors in advertisements or product descriptions. Policies, item availability and prices are subject to change without notice. 

* * *

**Additional Information**

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to 

[privacypolicy@creativepro.com](mailto:privacypolicy@creativepro.com). 

* * *  
  
---|---
